Hello friends A very warm welcome to all of you once again in VLE Society!
Friends, today in this video we will talk about CSC VLE brothers!
Very big update Very big good news as you all know!
For a long time many VLE brothers are being told this to many people!
Now that the CSC VLE has a payout of Rs.15 hundred per month!
It will be given, as salary and which VLE will get it!
Or everyone will get, how will you check, how will the registration happen, what is the service for this!
Today in this video I will tell A to Z information!
But friends, as always before starting the video, if you are new to the channel!
So do subscribe the channel and press the bell icon!
If you like the video then don't forget to reach out to other friends by liking the video!
So that everyone can know about it, okay!
So without delay, first of all friends, let me tell you about the service!
Although I have written a detail article here, on the website of VLE Society!
The link has been given in the video description from where you can go within the important news!
You will be able to read the whole A to Z important process of this Sara!
How will you get it but before that let me tell you!
In our DSK group, I will show what has been posted by our district manager today!
And what are the things mentioned, all right!
Because if you are a CSC VLE then if I tell you!
You must have received some such information from the District Manager!
If he has not come, then you will contact him, then I think whenever he comes, he will definitely tell you! Alright !
So look here first of all what has been written, only these gram panchayats have
to have PLV registration, so VLE brothers of the concerned gram panchayat make sure to enroll today!
Under the above scheme, Rs 1500 per month is proposed to be paid to PLV, okay!
Means to say, here on the registration of PLV, you will get Rs 1500 per month!
Payment will be made in CSC VLE brother's dgpay but it is written here!
Registration of PLV is to be done only in these Gram Panchayats, okay!
So in which gram panchayats you have to register PLV here!
How do you know this, I will tell all the things now!
But first of all know that PLV and what is this project within it!
And for whom 1500 rupees is being given!
You must have come to know that all VLEs will be given or not given!
That will be given only in selected Gram Panchayats! But how do you check?
Whether it will be given or not given in your Gram Panchayat, it is okay!
Whatever I have given a link to the article! Anytime you go there!
So here I have given A to Z information!
If you do not know about this project, then I will tell you what it is!
So guys there is a project by doing CSC Tele Law and if you don't know!
So tele law I have given the link, you can go from there also, you will search directly on google!
Then you will be on the Telelaw website, all right!
So what's inside the tele law that whenever someone is a victim!
Suppose there is a small child, he is being harassed, some is a daughter-in-law, some is a laborer, he is not getting wages!
Or how did he guarantee that you bought something!
You haven't received the warranty yet! Something you ordered is not returning!
If there is any problem with this method, your right is dying anywhere!
And you want to take action against him but due to lack of information!
You are not able to take any action against him, okay!
So here the government has created a portal for free legal advice!
What is CSC Tele Law within, anyone can take their legal advice which is absolutely free of cost from a High Court lawyer!
If you go to a lawyer here and there, it's a little more expensive, okay!
So here one can get free legal advice by getting their hair registered through the nearest CSC center!
Especially women, so friends here to do this thing well!
What has the government done here to make this thing accessible to the public!
Each CSC center has been appointed to give one PLV each!
That PLV will sit at each center, which will tell the villagers!
Those who have problems regarding this scheme will bring them to the CSC center!
And will register on their hair portal so that they can be helped, all right!
So as I have given you an interview with a PLV here!
So you will definitely see this too, what do you do with PLVs!
You'll find out how they work and all that, okay!
So this PLV will get Rs 1500 per month salary as salary!
And whatever hair you register, twenty or thirty rupees will also be paid on it according to the hair, well, every month!
But it is mandatory to have at least 10 hair registers every month!
Other wise you won't get a penny, okay!
So right now whenever you have to register for PLV here, it's fine!
So what you have to do for this is to go to this portal and log in with digital service!
After clicking on Login with Digital Seva your user profile will ask for update!
So here first of all VLE Name Male Female Whoever it is!
His mobile number, state, district and whatever the block is!
All those things you thought, here you have to click on submit!
And after filling all this information, you have to click on submit!
And by clicking on submit, your registration will be successful, Vle Wala!
So now what to do after this, you have to get on the dash board like this!
And after visiting this dashboard, what you have to do, look, you will get an option of PLV registration!
Simply click on it, and as soon as you click!
So here you will get the option of check availability by entering your CSCID!
So here you have to check by simply entering your CSCID!
And if your showing this available on CSCID!
Then you have to fill in a PLV information here, OK!
Whatever PLV you are making here, try to be female!
And if he has done any course of PMG direction etc., then it is very good thing from you here!
Here many people have to ask whose name, address etc. will be there!
So whatever PLV's you are registering here, it is so well written!
What is his mobile number, e-mail id, where does he live!
You have to fill all that information here!
After filling all this information, now you have to register whatever PLV you are doing here!
Upload their photo signature and the one who is their CV!
So I have given the format of CV, link in the download description from where you can download and make a CV!
For your operator, whoever you are registering for PLV in this, right
and after doing all this work here, now you will see the submit button below here!
So simply click on Save, after verifying all the information!
As soon as you do, see this successful registration will come!
That you have to register PLV!
Now where to go you have to click on Book Appointment!
You have to go back to your dashboard and register at least 10 cases every month!
Only then you will get the money of PLV and its case register!
So what you have to do now, if you have already added a beneficiary!
So you will search by entering its number, you will click on OtherWise Ad Beneficiary!
And whoever has a problem, whoever needs legal advice!
You have to fill their details here, and after ticking that!
Fill in their name and mobile number, address etc. Everything!
If they have any government ID proof, put that!
And then put OTP in PLV by doing Directed by Vle!
And that has to be done by clicking on Save and Proceed!
And after doing so much work, now look at you here, the beneficiary ad will come by writing successful!
And after that you see there will also be an option to book appointment, OK!
So simply click on Book Appointment!
And as soon as you click on it, a page like this will come in front of you!
Where you have to add the case description!
Whoever has any problem, you can write it here!
Or he has an attachment, he can put it!
And in case type you have to click on the instant one!
And here the name of the lawyer has to be selected, from which lawyer you have to book, with whom to do it, okay!
So after entering the name of that lawyer, click on submit here!
As soon as you submit, the case in front of you will be loaded successfully!
Now whatever time and time you have got, at that time you will get that beneficiary to talk to the lawyer!
Or he will then call them on mobile and talk to them and give them advice!
That's what they should do, and so much of your work ends here, okay!
So I hope you all have understood this completely!
If you like the video then you will definitely share it with all your friends.
See you all in the new video till then bye bye Jai Hind!